

Stuttgart, Germany
+49 178 133 9024
waldemar.reusch@gmail.com
GitHub
linkedin

Java	
TypeScript	
Python	
React	
Quarkus	
Git	
PostgreSQL	
German	
Fnglish	

Profile

I specialize in crafting and enhancing web applications with a strong focus on sustainable architecture and user-friendly design. My expertise spans the entire software development lifecycle, from inception to deployment, ensuring a seamless user experience at every layer, from the backend database to the end-user interface.

Employment History

Systems Engineer at AnyDesk Software GmbH, Stuttgart

JANUARY 2021 - PRESENT

Technical Product Management for the development of the user- and device management software my.anydesk. Analysis of previous work, development of a new architecture and establishment of an proof-of-concept. Continuous contribution to the product development, database and interface designs, requirement engineering and stakeholder communication.

Establishment of a new Software Team consisting of Frontend-, Backend- and Full-Stack-Engineers. On- and off-boarding and mentoring. Technical and managerial Leadership.

Establishment of Software Development Life Cycles and Documentation processes, customized for challenges and requirements particular to this team.

Consultancy of adjacent teams on topics of automation and interface design for established and novel products and tools.

Java, TypeScript, Quarkus, Vert.X, React, Next.js, PostgreSQL, Gitlab, Docker, Jira, Confluence

Software and Platform Engineeer at Insilico Biotechnology AG, Stuttgart

MARCH 2015 - DECEMBER 2020

Development of a machine learning pipeline to create customized predictive hybrid models for the analysis of bioprocess performance and various optimization scenarios including a data-lake and a custom task scheduler.

Contribution of software engineering expertise throughout the software development lifecycle, from requirements, through design and implementation to deployment and in all layers between database, middleware, grid engine and user interface.

Maintenance and administration of IT infrastructure, CI pipelines and containerized applications on premise and on AWS.

Python, Java, jupyter notebooks, gitlab, AWS, PostgreSQL, Oracle DB, HTCondor, Jira, Confluence

Education

Dipl. Biology, t. o. at the University of Stuttgart

OCTOBER 2007 - NOVEMBER 2014

Diploma thesis on the development of a bioinformatic data warehouse application including middleware, API and UI, capable of holding and managing protein sequence, structure and function information, using PHP, Perl, HTML, CSS and JavaScript. The system is publicly available for scientific use on https://biocatnet.de.

Certifications

How to manage a Remote Team at Coursera

SEPTEMBER 2023

Challanges of managing remote teams and how to overcome them.

Certified Java EE Workshop at PC College, Stuttgart

MARCH 2017

Thorough workshop on many aspects of Java EE with real-world examples.